Personal
Marist Archives and Special Collections
Personal
2.1.3.1.1.4
Marist College
MMM
MMM
MMM
  Box 1496
- Personal, 2.1.3.1.1.4
  - Personal, 1918; 60 (Box 1496)
    - Lowell Thomas in Arab headdress, 1
  - Personal, 1918; 61 (Box 1496)
    - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas squatting in front of tent, Arabia, 1
  - Personal, 1918; 62 (Box 1496)
    - Lowell Thomas and T.E. Lawrence standing in front of tent, Arabia, 1
    - Verso: L.T. (profile) with Colonel T.E. Lawrence, standing in front of Lawrence's tent, in the Arabia desert, 1-verso
  - Personal, circa 1919; 63 (Box 1496)
    - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas, three quarter view, bushes, full-faced, in Arab clothes, 1
  - Personal, circa 1919; 64 (Box 1496)
    - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas in Arab clothes, full-faced, with sickly smiles, 1
  - Personal, circa 1919; 65 (Box 1496)
    - T. E. Lawrence and Lowell Thomas in Arab clothes, side view, laughing, 1
  - Personal, 1918; 66 (Box 1496)
    - Lowell Thomas on Arab horse [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: An Arab thoroughbred], 1
  - Personal, 1918; 67 (Box 1496)
    - Lowell Thomas on Emir Feisal's horse, 1
  - Personal, 1918; 68 (Box 1496)
    - Lowell Thomas on Emir Feisal's Arabian horse, 1
  - Personal, 1918; 69 (Box 1496)
    - Profile view of Lowell Thomas and General Edmund Allenby, close-up [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Allenby and author], 1
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas and Lord Allenby who drove the Turks from the Holy Land and freed Jerusalem, 1-verso
  Box 1497
- Personal, 2.1.3.1.1.4
  - Personal, 1918; 1 (Box 1497)
    - Lowell Thomas with movie camera in airplane before taking off for a flight from Egypt to Jerusalem [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lowell Thomas in an open cockpit Breguet about to take off with Major A. J. Evans to follow the route of the Israelites across the Sinai Desert], 1
    - Verso: L.T. before taking off for a flight from Egypt to Jerusalem over the Sinai Desert. It took the Israelites 40 years to get over the desert part. L.T. made it in 40 minutes, from the borders of Egypt to the Plains of Philistia, 1-verso
    - Lowell Thomas ready for flight, in old-fashioned observation plane, from Cairo to Jerusalem during World War in Near East, 2
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas ready for flight, in old-fashioned observation plane, from Cairo to Jerusalem during World War in Near East, 2-verso
    - L.T. all set to make the first motion picture record, from the air, of the British Army's advance across the Sinai Desert, from Egypt to Palestine, along the same route followed by Moses and the Israelites, 3
    - Verso: L.T. all set to make the first motion picture record, from the air, of the British Army's advance across the Sinai Desert, from Egypt to Palestine, along the same route followed by Moses and the Israelites, 3-verso
    - LT in plane, landscape, 4
    - LT in plane, portrait with border, 5
    - LT in plane, landscape with border, 6
    - Lowell Thomas while filming the operations of Allenby's Cavalry, during the war against the Turks in the Holy Land., 7
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas while filming the operations of Allenby's Cavalry, during the war against the Turks in the Holy Land., 7-verso
    - Mr. Thomas with movie camera in Aeroplane [sic], 8
    - Verso: Mr. Thomas with movie camera in Aeroplane [sic], 8-verso
    - LT in plane, landscape, 9
    - LT in plane, portrait large, 10
    - Lowell Thomas while filming the operations of Allenby's Cavalry, during the war against the Turks in the Holy Land., 11
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas while filming the operations of Allenby's Cavalry, during the war against the Turks in the Holy Land., 11-verso
  - Personal, 1918; 2 (Box 1497)
    - Lowell Thomas with mayor of Gaza having a quiet smoke, the mayor's nephews at right [8 copies], 1
    - Verso: Mr. Thomas + Mayor of Gaza + Nephews smoking pipe, 1-verso
  - Personal, 1918; 3 (Box 1497)
    - Lowell Thomas taking notes alongside a disabled tank near Gaza, 1
    - Verso: British tank put out of commission during second battle of Gaza, 1-verso
    - Mr. Thomas + Tank near Gaza, Palestine [4 copies], 2
    - Verso: Mr. Thomas + Tank near Gaza, Palestine, 2-verso
    - Lowell Thomas taking notes alongside a disabled tank near Gaza [2 copies], 3
    - Lowell Thomas taking notes alongside a disabled tank near Gaza [large landscape], 4
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas, when he was a World War correspondent, inspecting a tank that has been badly smashed in an engagement, 4-verso
  - Personal, 1918; 4 (Box 1497)
    - Harry Chase and two men examine a tank, 1
    - Verso: British tank left on battlefield outside Gaza during second disasterous battle, 1-verso
  - Personal, 1918; 5 (Box 1497)
    - Lowell Thomas in armored car in the valley of the Dead Sea, 1000 feet below sea level [2 copies], 1
    - Lowell Thomas in armored car in the valley of the Dead Sea, 1000 feet below sea level, 2
  - Personal, 1917; 6 (Box 1497)
    - Leaning Tower of Pisa, Lowell Thomas, Mrs. Frances Ryan Thomas, and Major Piero Tozzi in foreground [4 copies], 1
  - Personal, 1917; 7 (Box 1497)
    - Lowell Thomas and Major Barracca and others, airplane in background, 1
    - Verso: Major Barracca, Italian ace of aces shaking hands with Lowell Thomas, the American traveloguer, 1-verso
    - Lowell Thomas and Major Baracca, 2
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas and Major Baracca, 2-verso
    - Major Barracca, greatest Italian Ace., 3
    - Verso: Major Barracca, greatest Italian Ace., 3-verso
    - Lowell Thomas and Major Barracca and others, airplane in background, 4
    - Lowell Thomas and Major Barracca and others [large landscape], 5
    - Verso: Maj. Baracca - Italy Ace. Autumn 1917; Italy, 5-verso
  - Personal, circa 1919; 8 (Box 1497)
    - Harry Chase in Arab clothes, three quarter view, London, 1
    - Verso: Harry Chase, 1-verso
  - Personal, 1918; 9 (Box 1497)
    - Veiled woman of Arabia [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Types of city head-dress for women], 1
  - Personal, 1918; 10 (Box 1497)
    - Veiled woman, full length, aboard ship [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Types of city head-dress for women], [2 copes], 1
    - Verso: A high-class Arab woman. They all wear veils over their faces and no man is allowed to look behind a woman's veil unless he is her father or her husband or her brother, 1-verso
  - Personal, 1918; 11 (Box 1497)
    - Veiled woman, Dorothy Waldegrave as Miss America, Major Peter Drummond, Lieutenant McCall McCowan, more serious, 1
  - Personal, 1918; 12 (Box 1497)
    - Sketch of Lowell Thomas by James McBey [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The author sketched by James McBey, official artist for Allenby's forces in the Holy Land], 1
    - Verso: Lowell Thomas. King Edward Hotel. Sketch by James McBey. Greatest etcher since Whistler. Please return immediately, 1-verso
    - Sketch of Lowell Thomas by James McBey [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: The author sketched by James McBey, official artist for Allenby's forces in the Holy Land], 2
    - Verso: Arabia, 2-verso
  - Personal, 1918; 13 (Box 1497)
    - Lowell Thomas and man wielding a rifle on Mount Hor [2 copies], 1
    - Verso: L.T. on the left, with a member of his bedouin bodyguard, making notes at the Tomb of Aaron, brother of Moses, on Mt. Hor, in Arabia. [Stamp: Sep 18 1938 Boston Herald], 1-verso
    - Aaron's tomb on Summit of Mt. Hor == Arabia [2 copies], 2
    - Verso: Aaron's tomb on Summit of Mt. Hor == Arabia, 2-verso
  - Personal, 1918; 14 (Box 1497)
    - Lowell Thomas in Arab headdress, close-up[Lowell Thomas autographed all eight items] [With Lawrence in Arabia caption: Lowell Thomas in Arab costume when he was with Lawrence of Arabia], 1
  - Personal, circa 1918 - 1919; 15 (Box 1497)
    - Lowell Thomas poses holding pith helmet, 1
  - Personal, circa 1918 - 1919; 16 (Box 1497)
    - Lowell Thomas poses wearing pith helmet, close-up, 1
    - Verso: Return to Joseph Kaye 403 E 5th St, New York, NY, 1-verso
    - Lowell Thomas poses wearing pith helmet, close-up [2 copies], 2
    - Verso: L.T. in Palestine, 2-verso
  - Personal, circa 1918 - 1921; 17 (Box 1497)
    - T. E. Lawrence in white robes, 1
  - Personal, 1918; 18 (Box 1497)
    - Lowell Thomas and T. E. Lawrence squat in front of tent, distant view, 1
    - Lowell Thomas and T. E. Lawrence squat in front of tent, distant view, 2
  - Personal, 1918; 19 (Box 1497)
    - Lowell Thomas in airplane, 1
    - Note: L.T. in rear cockpit about to take off on the first passenger airplane flight from Egypt to the Holy Land, over the wilderness where Moses and the Israelites wandered for forty years, 2
  - Personal, circa 1920; 20 (Box 1497)
    - [New Zealand] Wellington panorama from hill overlooking center of city, big bare space in foreground, 1
  - Personal, circa 1920; 21 (Box 1497)
    - [New Zealand] Wellington panorama from hill overlooking center of city, slightly more distant view (badly spotted), 1
  - Personal, circa 1920; 22 (Box 1497)
    - [New Zealand] Wellington panorama from hill overlooking center of city, side view taken from hill just above tram line, 1
  - Personal, circa 1920; 23 (Box 1497)
    - [New Zealand] Suburb of Wellington on shore of Cook Strait, Lowell Thomas stands on cannon in foreground, 1
  - Personal, circa 1920; 24 (Box 1497)
    - [New Zealand] Similar to 6-3 showing less of city and more flowers in foreground, 1
  - Personal, circa 1920; 25 (Box 1497)
    - [New Zealand] Wellington from hill near tea kiosk with tree on right side, 1
  - Personal, circa 1920; 26 (Box 1497)
    - [New Zealand] Extinct volcano near Wairaki, 1
    - Verso: Extinct Volcano, 1-verso